Ankush Rana

Contact

Address

Gardenia Village , Doha Qatar

Phone

+974 70562014

E-mail

ankush_rana61@yahoo.com

WWW

https://bold.pro/my/ankush-rana-230620040407/580

Skills

Additional Information

I.T. Skills: Proficient user of

MS Office Applications, Email & Internet

Interests: Enjoys socializing with family and friends

Operations support

Performance improvement

Safe handling

Food preparation and safety

Cuisine- French, Italian, Mediterranean,British and Indian

Schedule Management

Plating

A hardworking and service orientated culinary professional with over 12 years of proven work experience in various prestigious hotels, restaurants and cruise in Dubai, India, China, USA and Qatar. Highly organized with excellent time management skills, successfully manages heavy workloads and ensure all objectives are met within the agreed timeframes. Customer focused, always aims to deliver excellent quality and tantalizing dishes beyond the customer's expectation. Enjoys learning new skills and demonstrates my creative flair in the presentation of all the dishes I prepares. Now seeking a new opportunity where I can gain further skills; whilst adding value and contributing to the success of my prospective employer.

Work History

2022-10 -Current

Sous Chef

St Regis Hotel (Roberto's Italian Restaurant), Marsa Arabia , Doha

- Planned and directed high-volume food preparation in fast-paced environment.
- Prevented cross-contamination from utensils, surfaces, and pans when cooking and plating meals for food allergy sufferers.
- Initiated training for new team members on culinary techniques to improve productivity and increase kitchen workflows.
- Collaborated with staff members to create meals for large banquets.
- Trained kitchen staff to perform various preparation tasks under pressure.
- Maintained up-to-date knowledge of current culinary trends and techniques.

2020-01 -

Sous chef

2022-09

Virgin Voyage Cruise,, Miami, FL

 Worked in Razzle - Dazzle (international cuisine restaurant).

2018-01 -2019-12

Sous chef (acting head chef)

Peregrines food jubilee hills Hyderabad India, SSK

 Essence fusion a modern Indian cuisine and Aura café (times food award winner casual dining café).

2016-10 - 2017-12	Chef de Partie Waldorf Astoria, Dubai Palm Jumeirah, HILTON hotels In Social by Heinz back (Michelin star Italian chef)
2015-04 - 2016-09	Demi Chef De Partie Galaxy Hotel, Galaxy Entertainment Group, Macau,
	 SAR Otto E Mezzo Bombana 1* Michelin Italian restaurant.
2014-03 - 2015-03	Commis Chef
	 Grosvenor House, A Luxury Collection Hotel, Dubai U.A.E In Rhodes W 1 (A modern British Cuisine by Michelin star chef Gary Rhodes)
2012-10 - 2014-02	Commis Chef
	One & Only Royal Mirage, DubaiNina (a modern Indian cuisine)
2012-01 - 2012-10	Double Tree by Hilton, Gurgaon New Delhi Italian cuisine) as a Commis
2010-12 -	Commis Chef
2011-12	Devyani Food Street Pvt. Ltd, IGI Airport, Delhi , Delhi

Education

Food spoilage prevention

Food plating and

Fine-dining expertise

Sanitation guidelines

HACCP, Public Health

presentation

Diploma: food production

Institute of Hotel Management Dehradun India.

certificate in computer application

APPICL Institute of Computer Technology Ltd